Guide to the photograph album Orientreise 1898 AD.MC.062
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Orientreise 1898
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
The Wayfarer's Bookshop
Unknown
AD.MC.062
110 Photographic Prints Folio (37x28 cm). 24 leaves. With 110 gelatin silver photographs numbered mounted (recto & verso) in twenty-four leaves. Photos mostly ca. 10x15 cm (4x6 in) with twenty-four smaller images. [With] two manuscript lists describing the photos. Original red gilt lined half morocco album with red cloth boards with stamped gilt title on front cover. Mounts a little waved, extremities very mildly rubbed, but overall a very good album of strong photographs.
An album of photographs that document a voyage made in 1898. The majority of the photos show Egypt, Palestine, Lebanon, Syria and Turkey. The photographs show coastal and port scenes, city and street views, historical sights, images of the travellers and onboard life. Of note is an accompanying handwritten content list and note book (in German).
Box AD_MC_062
Content Description
Album containing 110 gelatin silver photographs which document a voyage made in February and March 1898, which took the photographer from Genoa to Monaco, Tunis, Alexandria, Cairo (and environs), Jerusalem, Dead Sea, Beirut, Damascus and then the return voyage via Constantinople, Athens, Crete, Palermo, Naples and finally the Genoa suburb of La Mortola. The photographs show coastal and port scenes, city and street views, historical sights, images of the travellers and onboard life. The majority of the photos show Egypt, Palestine, Lebanon, Syria and Turkey.
Photos mostly ca. 10x15 cm (4x6 in) with twenty-four smaller images. Accompanying handwritten content list and note book in German.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Akkasah Photography Archive, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from The Wayfarer's Bookshop in January 2017, associated accession identifier 2017_023.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical / Historical
The creator/s of the album are unknown. They/their fellow travellers are pictured in refs AD_MC_062_ref16, ref22, ref23, ref26, ref41, ref46-ref48, ref50 and ref52.
Photographic Prints; Egypt; Palestine; Lebanon; Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Athens, Greece; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Travel; The Wayfarer's Bookshop
- The front cover of the album 'Orientreise, 1898'., AD_MC_062_ref1; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  German Writing; Egypt; Syria; Lebanon; Palestine; Istanbul, Turkey; Greece; Italy
- The inside front cover of the album 'Orientreise, 1898'., AD_MC_062_ref2; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Palestine; Egypt; Syria; Lebanon; Greece; Italy
- A blank page in the album 'Orientreise, 1898'., AD_MC_062_ref3; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Syria; Palestine; Lebanon; Egypt; Istanbul, Turkey; Greece; Italy
- A blank page in the album 'Orientreise, 1898'., AD_MC_062_ref4; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Syria; Lebanon; Egypt; Palestine; Istanbul, Turkey; Greece; Italy
- Two views of the Port of Genoa and the surrounding city., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref5; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Ports; Water; Clocks/Watches; Mountains/Hills; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Women; Individual Portraits; Flags; Unknown Locations; Coast
- Top: a view of the Rock of Monaco. Bottom: French warships sailing near a French port., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref6; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Mountains/Hills; Monaco; Ports; Coast; Mediterranean Sea; Water; Seas; Buildings; Architecture; Landscapes; Men
- Top: a view of trees and cacti in the mountains, and a railway in Djedeida that runs between Bizerte and Tunis. Bottom: a view of a Tunis taken from the surrounding hills., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref7; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Tunis, Tunisia; Countryside/Rural; Railways; Transportation; Hats; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Architecture; Landscapes
- Top: men, women, and children outside the bazaar in Tunis. Bottom: A view of men, women, and children at a marketplace in Bab Souika, Tunis., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref8; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunis, Tunisia; Regional/National Dress; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Women; Boys; Children; Facial Hair
- Top: a man next to two camels. Bottom: a view of the Parc du Belvédère in Tunis, with a mountain in the background., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref9; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Camels; Animals; Streets/Roads; Men; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; Countryside/Rural; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Outdoors; Tunis, Tunisia; Gardens
- Top: a group of ships arriving to a port in Alexandria, with the guide book in the foreground. Bottom: a group of banana boats on the Nile River in El Mahmoudia, Alexandria., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref10; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Regional/National Dress; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Water; Transportation; Palm Trees; Rivers; Buildings; Architecture; Lighthouses; Alexandria, Egypt
- Top: an empty field next to a river with mountains in the background in Cairo. Bottom: boats docked in a canal on the Nile River., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref11; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Flags; Mountains/Hills; Mosques; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Rivers; Buildings; Canals; Cairo, Egypt; Countryside/Rural; Nile River
- Top: people in the streets beside the Mausoleum of Mamluk Amir Janibak al-Ashrafi (foreground) and Funerary Khanqah of Mamluk Sultan Faraj ibn Barquq (background). Bottom: A shop with a printing press, near Bab Zuweila., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref12; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tombs/Mausoleums; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Boys; Children; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Markets; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Shops; Street Vendors; Workers; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Mosques; Religious Sites; Horses; Animals
- Top: a farm with buildings on the horizon in Boulaq, Cairo. Bottom: a caravan., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref13; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Buildings; Palm Trees; Agriculture/Farms; Countryside/Rural; Camels; Animals; Machines; Men; Regional/National Dress; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Cairo, Egypt
- Top: a caravan on the Avenue of the Pyramids in Giza. Bottom: a canal and and fig trees., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref14; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Streets/Roads; Camels; Animals; Men; Group Portraits; Canals; Forest/Woodlands; Gardens; Parks; Water; Giza, Egypt
- Top: buildings on the bank of Roda Island, Cairo. Bottom: a farm in Heliopolis with donkeys and machinery., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref15; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Coast; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Buildings; Mosques; Donkeys; Animals; Countryside/Rural; Men; Cannons; Group Portraits; Weapons; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Nile River; Fishing; Outdoors; Religious Sites; Cairo, Egypt
- Top: A group portrait of several men and a woman in front of the Cheops Pyramid and the Sphinx. Bottom: the Sphinx and the Great Pyramids., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref16; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Women; Hats; Canes/Walking Sticks; Men; Group Portraits; Camels; Animals; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Fez/Tarboush; Cairo, Egypt
- Top: a group of people climbing the Great Pyramids. Bottom: the town of Bedrachein on the Nile River., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref17; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Regional/National Dress; Women; Group Portraits; Giza, Egypt; Cairo, Egypt; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Head Covers/Veils; Animals; Fez/Tarboush; Boats/Ships; Rivers; Water; Nile River; Buildings; Architecture; Transportation; Palm Trees
- Top: a palm tree forest in Memphis. Bottom: a group of men traveling to the Pyramid of Djoser., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref18; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Countryside/Rural; Palm Trees; Landscapes; Memphis, Egypt; Pyramids; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Donkeys; Men; Group Portraits; Giza, Egypt; Hats; Canes/Walking Sticks
- Top: a crowd of people and donkeys in Saqqara. Bottom: a street scene beside Jaffa Gate including a photography studio and barbers., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref19; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Crowds; Deserts; Landscapes; Donkeys; Men; Animals; Group Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Signs/Signposts; Shops; Fez/Tarboush; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Saqqara, Egypt; Architecture; Jaffa Gate, Jerusalem; Jerusalem
- Top: the Tower of David (Jerusalem Citadel). Bottom: a view of the Mount of Olives, Jerusalem., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref20; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jerusalem; Architecture; Tower of David/Burj Dāwūd (Jerusalem Citadel); Religious Sites; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Church of Mary Magdalene, Jerusalem; Churches; Buildings; Gardens; Parks; Mountains/Hills; Men; Women; Hats; Horses; Group Portraits
- Top: a crowd of men and women at the base of the Mount of Olives, Jerusalem. Bottom: a view of Siloam., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref21; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Jerusalem; Church of Mary Magdalene, Jerusalem; Churches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Hats; Donkeys; Animals; Boys; Children; Regional/National Dress; Gardens; Parks; Mountains/Hills; Facial Hair; Siloam/Silwan; Buildings; Architecture; Landscapes
- Top: a group portrait of two men and a woman posed outside a tent in Jericho. Bottom: a man posed by the cost of the Dead Sea., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref22; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats; Tents; Countryside/Rural; Water; Coast; Individual Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Binoculars; Jericho; Dead Sea
- Top: A group portrait of men and women on the coast of the Dead Sea. Bottom: a view of the River Jordan with a woman in the foreground., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref23; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Coast; Mountains/Hills; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats; Facial Hair; Rivers; Outdoors; Dead Sea; Landscapes; Jordan River; Seas
- Top: a view of tents on the way from Jerusalem to Jericho. Bottom: a view of Beirut., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref24; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tents; Horses; Animals; Mountains/Hills; Outdoors; Jerusalem; Jericho; Coast; Water; Buildings; Architecture; Landscapes; Beirut, Lebanon
- Top: a boat sailing near the coast of Beirut. Bottom: a road in Mount Sannine near terraced farms., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref25; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Snow; Streets/Roads; Beqaa Valley, Lebanon; Beirut, Lebanon; Agriculture/Farms
- Top: a group of people congregated at the base of a terraced mountain town, Muallaqa (Zahle), on the way from Beirut to Damascus. Bottom: a train track in the Anti-Lebanon Mountains., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref26; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Children; Men; Women; Hats; Crowds; Mountains/Hills; Beirut, Lebanon; Donkeys; Animals; Landscapes; Railways; Transportation; Snow; Canes/Walking Sticks; Damascus, Syria; Anti-Lebanon Mountains
- Top: a man riding a camel in Muallaqa (Zahle). Bottom: a group of men gathered outside a building., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref27; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Camels; Animals; Beqaa Valley, Lebanon; Men; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Countryside/Rural; Buildings; Architecture; Canes/Walking Sticks; Unknown Locations
- Top: a man in the courtyard of the Umayyad Mosque. Bottom: an aerial view of Damascus., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref28; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Umayyad Mosque/Great Mosque of Damascus; Mosques; Religious Sites; Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Praying; Architecture; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Damascus, Syria
- Top: an aerial view of the Umayyad Mosque. Bottom: a fountain in the courtyard of a Christian house., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref29; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Damascus, Syria; Umayyad Mosque/Great Mosque of Damascus; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Women; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Fountains; Men
- Top: a bridge on the Barada River with the Tekkiye Mosque and Mount Hermon in the background. Bottom: a rooftop view of a city and a two-story arched dome., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref30; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Barada River; Rivers; Water; Mountains/Hills; Horses; Animals; Men; Buildings; Regional/National Dress; Mosques; Architecture; Damascus, Syria; Bridges; Mount Hermon/Jabal al-Shaykh, Lebanon; Unknown Locations
- Top: a vignetted street scene featuring a mosque. Bottom: the Bosporus Sea with Uskudar, Istanbul in the background., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref31; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Water; Buildings; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites; Streets/Roads; Men; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Shops; Seas; Bosphorus; Uskudar, Istanbul, Turkey; Unknown Locations
- Top: ships sailing off the coast of Istanbul. Bottom: a view of the Rumelihisarı., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref32; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Buildings; Mosques; Forts/Castles; Architecture; Cemeteries; Flags; Rumelihisari, Istanbul, Turkey; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Coast; Mountains/Hills
- Top: a view of the Rumelihisarı and adjacent buildings. Bottom: a ship sailing off the coast of Istanbul and the Dolmabahçe Palace (linked ref32)., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref33; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Forts/Castles; Architecture; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Coast; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Rumelihisari, Istanbul, Turkey; Dolmabahce Palace; Palaces
- Top: a view of Istanbul's coast including the Hagia Sophia and Topkapi Palace taken from the Bosphorus. Bottom: a cargo ship from Hamburg docked at a harbor in Piran., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref34; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Hagia Sophia; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Coast; Water; Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorus; Seas; Ports; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Unknown Locations; Flags; Men; Mountains/Hills
- Top: a ship sailing out of a port. Bottom: a ship "Auguste-Victoria" sailing adjacent to smaller rowboats., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref35; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Men; Mountains/Hills; Transportation; Water; Coast; Ports; Unknown Locations; Flags
- Top: a view of the Acropolis. Bottom: ruins of an ancient temple at the Acropolis., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref36; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Acropolis of Athens; Athens, Greece; Landscapes; Temples; Buildings; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Electricity
- Top: view of Athens taken from the Acropolis. Bottom: a view of the Erechtheion., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref37; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Temples; Mountains/Hills; Acropolis of Athens; Athens, Greece; Streets/Roads; Landscapes; Men; Women; Crowds; Group Portraits; Statues/Sculptures
- Top: a view of a Chania, Crete with mountains in the background. Bottom: the Port of Chania, Crete., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref38; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Ports; Coast; Unknown Locations; Water; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Architecture; Flags; Landscapes; Mosques; Religious Sites; Crowds; Hotels; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Men; Women; Children; Signs/Signposts; French Writing
- Top: a boat docked at the Port of Chania, Crete. Bottom: passengers on the deck of the "Auguste-Victoria" ship., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref39; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Hats; Facial Hair
- Two views of ships. Top: a ship in the south bay of Sardinia. Bottom: ships in a port in the moonlight., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref40; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Flags; Cannons; Weapons; Men; Unknown Locations
- Top: a view of Turkish forts. Bottom: a woman on a the deck of the "Auguste-Victoria" ship., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref41; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Coast; Ports; Water; Boats/Ships; Women; Transportation; Hats; Individual Portraits; Unknown Locations
- Top: a view of three boats off the coast of Palermo near Mount Pellegrino. Bottom: a body of water with ships and a city in the distance, taken from the "Auguste-Victoria" ship., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref42; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Boats/Ships; Transportation; Group Portraits; Men; Hats; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Unknown Locations
- Two views of the Villa Hanbury in La Mortola, Genoa., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref43; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gardens; Parks; Countryside/Rural; Forest/Woodlands; Buildings; Architecture; Outdoors; Italy
- Top: a view of the Villa Hanbury in La Mortola. Bottom: a fountain in La Mortola (linked ref43)., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref44; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Buildings; Gardens; Parks; Italy; Water; Palm Trees; Mountains/Hills; Fountains; Statues/Sculptures; Outdoors
- Top: foliage by a road. Bottom: a view of the mountainous coast in La Mortola., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref45; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Streets/Roads; Countryside/Rural; Pottery; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Coast; Water; Buildings; Italy
- From the top right counter-clockwise: a group portrait of several men at the Palace of the Bey (Dar el Bey), Tunis; the courtyard at the Palace of the Bey (Dar el Bey), Tunis; a group of men at the foot of the Sphinx; a view of the Great Pyramid and the Sphinx., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref46; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Hats; Palaces; Buildings; Architecture; Tunis, Tunisia; Group Portraits; Statues/Sculptures; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Pyramids; German Writing; Medals/Insignia; Binoculars; Giza, Egypt; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Canes/Walking Sticks; Landscapes
- From the top right counter-clockwise: two portraits of a crowd posed in front of the Sphinx and the Great Pyramid, a cemetery in Cairo, and the Mena House Hotel near the Great Pyramids., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref47; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; German Writing; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Men; Women; Camels; Animals; Facial Hair; Hats; Medals/Insignia; Binoculars; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Canes/Walking Sticks; Gloves; Fez/Tarboush; Crowds; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Hotels; Cemeteries; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Bow Ties; Cairo, Egypt
- From the top right counter-clockwise: men on the road in Saqqara, a group of men riding donkeys in Memphis, the village of Bedrechem, and a village in Saqqara., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref48; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; German Writing; Palm Trees; Streets/Roads; Countryside/Rural; Men; Women; Children; Workers; Agriculture/Farms; Donkeys; Animals; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Facial Hair; Water; Oases; Buildings; Crowds; Transportation; Saqqara, Egypt; Giza, Egypt; Memphis, Egypt
- From the top right counter-clockwise: the facade of the Ayyubid Omar Mosque, Jerusalem; a caravan's arrival in Bethlehem; the Umayyad Mosque in Damascus; and a Bedouin hotel in Jericho., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref49; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Mosques; Religious Sites; Jerusalem; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; German Writing; Bethlehem; Markets; Crowds; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Camels; Animals; Children; Women; Umayyad Mosque/Great Mosque of Damascus; Damascus, Syria; Jericho; Praying; Facial Hair; Horses; Hotels
- From the top right counter-clockwise: two views of a lunch spot on the way from Jerusalem to Jericho, the Acropolis, and ruins in Baalbek., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref50; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tents; Women; Men; Hats; Crowds; Mountains/Hills; Group Portraits; Jerusalem; Jericho; German Writing; Horses; Animals; Baalbek, Lebanon; Snow; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Acropolis of Athens; Athens, Greece; Temples; Buildings; Architecture; Food; Donkeys
- From the top right counter-clockwise: a view of the Rumelihisarı; the Port of Chania, Crete; a view of the Villa Durazzo-Pallavicini in Genoa; and a view of the deck on the Auguste in Victoria., 1898; AD_MC_062_ref51; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_062)